Michael P. Wingfield

371 E Allen St Apt 24, Castle Rock, CO 80108 720-971-4556 michael.p.wingfield@gmail.com

Game Programmer

Motivated and forward thinking software engineer dedicated to learning and improving.

Accomplished professional with a broad set of skills in software development and automated testing. Well developed communication and problem solving skills used effectively for working on and across teams. Experience with both small and large company environments and cultures.

Web Services ~ Server Implementation ~ Integration Automated Testing ~ Documentation ~ Nightly Deployment Performance Optimization ~ Sprint Planning ~ SCRUM

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Automated Test Engineer, Time Warner Cable, Broomfield, CO (July 2012 - Present)

Design and develop automated test plans for server-side products. Lead tester for Settings, Preferences and Profiles (SPP) product that manages and stores settings data for users across a broad range of devices. Implement tests for National Meta Data Database (NMD) with a focus on data validation across several server checkpoints from national to regional to client. Designed and developed an application using UDP instead of TCP to reduce network traffic between the server and client.

App Developer, Self Employed, Castle Rock, CO (May 2012 – July 2012)

Developed and published an app to the iOS app store for iPhone called "Cookin' Lists". Designed to help users with organizing to-do lists and grocery lists as well as a section for recipes and timers for cooking.

As the internship ended I decided to focus on an independent project to learn about mobile app development while looking for the next position in my career.

Software Engineer Intern, Wild Blue, Englewood, CO (May 2011 – May 2012)

Developed web apps for internal use in the NOC that analyzed and displayed information relating to the national health of the satellite network. Also developed plugins for the team's ticket tracking software that displayed relevant information using html and wiki formatting.

SELECTED TECHNICAL BACKGROUND

Programming: C#, Java, TestNG, Python, Javascript, Ruby on Rails, HTML, Objective C, MySQL, MongoDB, RESTful Webservices, and TCP/IP.

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, and Mac.

EDUCATION

University of Colorado - Colorado Springs, CO:

Bachelor of Innovation in Game Design and Development (September 2008 – May 2012)

PORTFOLIO

www.michaelwingfield.me